Finding Aid for Kenneth Ewart Boulding Papers 1880-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kenneth Ewart Boulding Papers
1880-1968
Boulding, Kenneth Ewart, 1910-
Professor of economics at the University of Michigan, director of the Center for Research on Conflict Resolution, fellow of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, and participant in the Society of Friends, the National Council of Churches Department of the Church and Economic Life, and peace and disarmament groups. Correspondence, notes, writings, photographs, recordings, and topical files; also materials concerning his wife, Elise Boulding, and his parents, William and Elizabeth Boulding.
85959 Aa 2
46.4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Kenneth Boulding (donor no. 4516 ) in 1967, with a small addition in 1969.
The collection is open for research.
Kenneth Ewart Boulding, professor of economics and pacifist, was born in Liverpool, England, January 18, 1910. He was educated at New College, Oxford, England (1928-1932) and the University of Chicago (1932-1934). Boulding taught economics at Colgate (1937-1941), Fisk (1942-1943), Iowa State (1943-1946), and McGill University (1946-1947) before joining the University of Michigan as a professor of economics, 1949-1967. Since 1968, Boulding has been associated with the University of Colorado at Boulder as a professor of economics and director for the Program on General Social and Economic Dynamics and the Institute of Behavioral Science.
Some of his related activities and honors included receiving the John Bates Clark Medal for Economics for 1949; a fellowship at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1954-1955; visiting professorships in Jamaica (1959-1960) and Japan (1963-1964); and directing the University of Michigan Center for Research in Conflict Resolution (1964-1966). Boulding also wrote numerous books, articles, and book reviews. Boulding was active in several peace, anti-nuclear, and disarmament groups, notably the Society of Friends and the National Council of Churches Department of the Church and Economic Life, and UNESCO. His wife, Elise (Biorn-Hansen) Boulding, was a sociologist and also very active in the international peace movement, women's issues, and Quaker activities.
Kenneth Boulding viewed economics as a creative and philosophical integration of various disciplines--political science, sociology and anthropology. He coined the word "eiconics" to describe the weaving together and restructuring of interdisciplinary knowledge.
The Boulding papers, consisting of approximately 46 linear feet, fall into the following series and sub-series.
Correspondence (boxes 1-10)
Miscellaneous clippings and printed materials (box 10)
Lecture and reading notes (boxes 11-13)
Published and unpublished writings (boxes 14-18)
Family and personal files (boxes 19-22)
Elise Boulding (boxes 19-21)
Topical files:
Economics (boxes 23-24)
Social Sciences (boxes 25-30)
California Water Resources Study, 1958-1959 (boxes 24-26)
Religion (boxes 30-31)
National Council of Churches of Christ, Department of the Church and Economic Life (boxes 30-31)
Peace, Conflict Resolution and Disarmament (boxes 32-38)
Center for Research on Conflict Resolution (boxes 32-34)
University of Michigan (boxes 39-42)
Travel (box 42)
Foundations (box 42)
Speaking Engagements (box 43)
Financial Records (boxes 44-45)
Sound recordings (box 46)
Photographs (box 47)
Subjects:
American Friends Service Committee.; Boulding, Kenneth E. (Kenneth Ewart), 1910-1993; California.; Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, Calif.); Disarmament.; Economics.; National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America.; Peace--Societies, etc.; Society for General Systems Research.; Society of Friends--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Center for Research on Conflict Resolution.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Economics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Water-supply.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Boulding, Elise.; Boulding, Kenneth E. (Kenneth Ewart), 1910-1993; Camps--Great Britain.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Great Britain.; Interiors.; Peace conferences.
Contributors:
Boulding, Elise.
Genre/Form:
Ambrotypes.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - By date
    - Undated, 1880-June 1936; 42 folders (Box 1)
    - July 1936-September 1943, 35 folders (Box 2)
    - October 1943-1949, 43 folders (Box 3)
    - 1950-April 1953, 35 folders (Box 4)
    - May 1953-1955, 30 folders (Box 5)
    - 1956-1958, 24 folders (Box 6)
      (undated and miscellaneous 1958)
    - 1958-1960, 21 folders (Box 7)
    - 1961-August 1962, 25 folders (Box 8)
    - September 1962-August 1964, 23 folders (Box 9)
    - September 1964-1966, 10 folders (Box 10)
  - By topic
    - Curriculum Resources, Inc., 1963-1964; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - International Christian University, 1964 (Box 10)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Japan Disarmament Study (DART)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous (scattered dates) (Box 10)
    - John Plott, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
    - Quaker Research Fund, 1962 (Box 10)
    - University of Michigan, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1964 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous clippings and printed materials (scattered dates)
  - circa 1950-1959 (Box 10)
  - circa 1960-1968 (Box 10)
- Lecture and reading notes
  - 1928-1964 (Box 11)
  - 1928-1964 (Box 12)
    (continued)
  - 1928-1964 (Box 13)
- Published and unpublished writings (essays, poetry, etc.)
  - Bibliography, 1932-1967 (Box 14)
  - 1929-1936 (Box 14)
  - 1936-1949 (Box 15)
  - 1948-1955 (Box 16)
  - 1955-1959 (Box 17)
  - 1960-1968 (Box 18)
- Family and personal files
  - George Rowe and William Boulding (Box 19)
    (include sermons and school records)
  - Elizabeth Boulding, 1901-1961 (Box 19)
    (Include diaries, correspondence, articles, and poems)
  - Elise Boulding papers, 1933-1951 (Box 19)
    (include correspondence, school records, and material on the family and on socialism)
  - Elise Boulding papers, 1950-1966 (Box 20)
    (include correspondence, articles, and other materials primarily related to the peace movement and women)
  - Elise Boulding papers, 1963-1967 (Box 21)
    (include materials related to the International Peace Research Newsletter)
  - Kenneth Boulding Personal Files, 1910-1932 (Box 21)
    (include correspondence, diaries, writings, and school records)
  - Kenneth Boulding Personal Files, 1933-1962 (Box 22)
    (include correspondence, journals and material related to his courtship of Elise Boulding and marriage)
  - Boulding family miscellanea (Box 22)
- Topical files
  - Economics
    - American Association of University Professors, 1960 (Box 23)
    - American Economic Association, 1945-1966; 4 folders (Box 23)
    - American Economic Review, 1945-1948 (Box 23)
    - Charts, 1940-1952; 4 folders (Box 23)
    - College Retirement Equities Fund, 1958-1961; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Committee for Economic Development, 1960-1961 (Box 23)
    - Economic Development Conference, Havana, 1960 (Box 23)
    - Economics and Mankind study, 1962 (Box 23)
    - Economics in Action Program, Case Institute of Technology, 1956-1960; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Ford Foundation
      - Economics and the Behavioral Sciences, 1952-1953 (Box 23)
      - Economic Development and Administration, 1954 (Box 23)
      - Seminar in the Theory of the Firm, 1958; 7 folders (Box 23)
    - High School Teaching of Economics, 1963 (Box 24)
    - Iowa State College Financial Conference, 1948 (Box 24)
    - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1962 (Box 24)
    - McGill University, Curriculum, 1946 (Box 24)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research
      - Conference on Research in Income and Wealth, 1949-1950 (Box 24)
      - Conference on Research in Income and Wealth, 1959-1961 (Box 24)
      - Conference on Philanthropy, 1961; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - "Normal Accounting" (Box 24)
    - Ohio State University Conference on Economics of Research and Development, 1962 (Box 24)
    - Quaker Economists, 1953-1958 (Box 24)
    - Savings and Residential Financing Conference, Chicago, 1965 (Box 24)
  - Social Sciences
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1958-1966 (Box 24)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1961-1962 (Box 24)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1960-1963 (Box 24)
    - American-Psychiatric Association Meeting, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Artorga, 1960-1961 (Box 24)
    - Brookings Institution, 1958-1963; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists Conference, 1963 (Box 24)
    - California Water Resources Study, 1958-1959
      - Correspondence, memoranda, and statements
        - Undated, September 1958; 6 folders (Box 24)
        - October 1958-1961, 8 folders (Box 25)
      - "Western Water News" (Box 25)
      - Huron River (Mich.) Watershed (Box 25)
      - Miscellanea (Box 25)
      - Reprints (Box 25)
      - Printed reports (Box 25)
      - Printed reports (cont.) (Box 26)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences
      - 1954-1955, 11 folders (Box 26)
      - 1954-1955, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Center for Integrated Studies, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Center for Productivity Motivation, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Citizens for Michigan, 1959 (Box 27)
    - City in History Conference, Boston, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Committee for Return of Confiscated German and Japanese Property, 1956-1960; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Committee for the Study of Mankind, 1958-1962; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Committee for World Development and Disarmament, 1959-1960 (Box 27)
    - Committee to Present Major Issues, 1960 (Box 27)
    - Duke University Symposium, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Foundation for Research on Human Behavior, 1958-1961 (Box 27)
    - General Electric Marketing Seminar
      - 1959 (Box 27)
      - 1959-1961 (Box 27)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 27)
    - Goals and Values in Agriculture Conference, Ames, Iowa, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Great Society Seminar, Syracuse, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Harris Foundation Conference, Chicago, 1947 (Box 27)
    - Hudson Institute, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Humanistic-Social Research Project, 1955 (Box 27)
    - Image of America, 1956-1961 (Box 27)
    - Information Retrieval Conference, Blue Mountain Lake, N.Y., 1961 (Box 27)
    - Institute for Policy Studies, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Institute of World Affairs, University of Southern California, 1964-1965 (Box 27)
    - Institute on Man and Science, 1966 (Box 27)
    - International Center in London for Non-Governmental Organizations, 1961 (Box 27)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1960-1962 (Box 27)
    - International Society for General Semantics, 1955-1965; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - International Studies Association, 1964-1965 (Box 27)
    - Japanese-American Round Table, 1962-1964; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Jersey Roundtable, 1956 (Box 27)
    - Labor in the Free Society Conference, Arden House, N.Y., 1958 (Box 28)
    - Market Models Conference, Arden House, N.Y., 1961 (Box 28)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Review of Progress in the Humanities, 1956 (Box 28)
    - Minnesota Library Association Meeting, 1961 (Box 28)
    - Modern Corporation: Its Images and Publics, Symposium, Gould House, N.Y., 1961 (Box 28)
    - National Academy of Sciences, Advisory Committee on Behavioral Science, 1961 (Box 28)
    - National Council for Civic Responsibility, 1964-1965 (Box 28)
    - National Federation of Settlements and Neighborhood Center, 1953-1958; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - National Manpower Council, 1953 (Box 28)
    - Nobel Conference, St. Peter, Minnesota, 1966 (Box 28)
    - Northwestern University
      - Program of Graduate Training in International Relations, 1959-1960 (Box 28)
      - Symposium, 1963 (Box 28)
      - Organizational Change Symposium, Montreal, 1964 (Box 28)
    - Pittsburgh University Administrative Science Center, 1958 (Box 28)
    - Political Sociology Conference, Kingston, Jamaica, 1961 (Box 28)
    - Positive Feedback Symposium, 1965 (Box 28)
    - Project Camelot, 1964-1965 (Box 28)
    - Pugwash Conference on Science and World Affairs
      - 10th, London, 1962 (Box 28)
      - 12th, Udaipur, India, 1964 (Box 28)
    - Salzburg Seminar, 1959; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Santa Barbara Institute of World Affairs, 1962 (Box 29)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1958-1960 (Box 29)
    - Society for General Systems Research, 1953-1966; 5 folders (Box 29)
    - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 1951-1954 (Box 29)
    - Society for the History of Technology, 1958 (Box 29)
    - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1962 (Box 29)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems, 1961 (Box 29)
    - Swarthmore Series in Social Justice, 1959-1961 (Box 29)
    - Theoretical Systems and Practical Decisions Seminar, Jamaica, 1959 (Box 29)
    - Theory and Method in Total Societies Conference (Box 29)
    - Washington, 1965; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - UNESCO, 1963-1965; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - United Nations University, 1961-1962 (Box 30)
    - Universal Knowledge Foundation, 1962 (Box 30)
    - Venezuela Conference, 1964 (Box 30)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1955-1965 (Box 30)
  - Religion
    - American Friends Service Committee
      - Regional, 1959-1961 (Box 30)
      - Philadelphia, 1960-1961 (Box 30)
      - Reciprocal International Seminar, 1961 (Box 30)
      - Bear Mountain Conference, 1961 (Box 30)
      - China Policy Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 30)
      - Working Party on Conscription, 1967; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Association of Religious Counselors (U-M), 1955-1958 (Box 30)
    - Christian Responsibility in Economic Decision Making Conference Washington, 1957 (Box 30)
    - Christianity and Economics, undated (Box 30)
    - Church and Society Conference, Geneva, 1966 (Box 30)
    - Faculty Christian Fellowship, 1952-1953 (Box 30)
    - Friends Activities (Miscellaneous)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 30)
      - 1957 (Box 30)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 30)
    - Friends Committee on National Legislation, 1953-1961 (Box 30)
    - Friends Journal, 1959-1961 (Box 30)
    - Friends Student Colony, Ames, Iowa, 1945-1946 (Box 30)
    - Friends World College, 1961 (Box 30)
    - Friends World Committee, 1959-1961 (Box 30)
    - Image of the University and Religious Work, 1965 (Box 30)
    - Michigan Pastors Conference, 1962 (Box 30)
    - National Council of Churches of Christ, Department of the Church and Economic Life
      - Correspondence, 1947-1963; 3 folders (Box 30)
      - Rules of Procedure (Box 30)
      - Annual Report, 1946-1961 (Box 30)
      - Newsletter, 1955-1959 (Box 30)
      - National Study Conference
        - Lst, Pittsburgh, 1947 (Box 30)
        - 2nd, Detroit, 1950 (Box 30)
        - 3rd, Pittsburgh, 1956 (Box 30)
        - 4th, Pittsburgh, 1962 (Box 30)
      - Christianity and the Economic Order
        - Series, 1946-1950 (Box 30)
        - Reactions, 1946-1950 (Box 30)
      - Ethics and Economics Study, outlines, 1950 (Box 31)
      - Ethics and Inflation, 1951 (Box 31)
      - Goals of Economic Life Project, 1950
        - Meetings and miscellanea (Box 31)
        - Papers, 4 folders (Box 31)
      - General papers, 1950-1966; 10 folders (Box 31)
      - Minutes, 1950-1962; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Pendle Hill, 1949-1966 (Box 31)
    - Quaker Program at the United Nations, 1960-1961 (Box 31)
    - Religious Organizations, miscellaneous, 1959-1961 (Box 31)
    - Religious Perspectives in College Teaching Seminar, Iowa City, 1957 (Box 31)
    - Science, Philosophy and Religion Conference, New York, 1959-1961 (Box 31)
    - Social Order Committee, 1959 (Box 31)
    - Society for the Scientific Study of Religion, 1955-1961; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Young Friends, 1957-1965 (Box 31)
  - Peace, Conflict Resolution, and Disarmament
    - Acts for Peace, 1961 (Box 32)
    - Anti-HUAC Petition, 1961 (Box 32)
    - Arden House Conference on Disarmament, 1956-1958 (Box 32)
    - Canadian Peace Research Institute, 1961-1966 (Box 32)
    - Causes of War Seminar, Montreal, 1961 (Box 32)
    - Center for Research on Conflict Resolution
      - Correspondence, 1960-1962; 10 folders (Box 32)
        (files A-S)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1962; 3 folders (Box 33)
        (files T-Z)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1963; 22 folders (Box 33)
        (files A-Z)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1962-1965; 4 folders (Box 33)
      - Minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 33)
      - Budgets and Grants, 1955-1966; 4 folders (Box 33)
      - Miscellanea and Mailing Lists, 1962-1964 (Box 33)
      - Fund Raising Letters, 1964-1965 (Box 33)
      - Draft Brochure, 1959 (Box 33)
      - Conferences and Research, 1959-1965; 4 folders (Box 33)
      - Journal of Conflict Resolution, 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, 1961 (Box 34)
    - Christian Assembly for Peace, Prague, 1961 (Box 34)
    - Christian Peace Conference, Prague, 1960 (Box 34)
    - Church Peace Union, 1959-1960 (Box 34)
    - Civil Liberties Committee, 1953 (Box 34)
    - Citizens Committee against the Trucks Law, 1952-1953 (Box 34)
    - Committee of Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 34)
    - Conflict in Society Symposium, London, 1965 (Box 34)
    - Creighton-Columbia Assembly, Omaha, 1961 (Box 34)
    - Current Thought on Peace and War, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Disarmament Reference File (arranged by author)
      - [A-B], 2 folders (Box 34)
      - [C-Mc], 11 folders (Box 35)
      - [M-Z], 10 folders (Box 36)
    - Economics of Disarmament Conference, Gould House, 1961 (Box 37)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation
      - 1956-1961 (Box 37)
      - 1962 (Box 37)
      - 1965 (Box 37)
    - Institute for International Order
      - Preparatory Conference on Factors Influencing International Peace, 1958-1960; 3 folders (Box 37)
      - Osborn Project, 1959-1961 (Box 37)
      - Peace Research Conference, 1961; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Intercollegiate Conference on Disarmament and Arms Control, Swarthmore, 1962 (Box 37)
    - International Arms Control Symposium, Philadelphia, 1966 (Box 37)
    - International Confederation for Disarmament and Peace, 1965-1966 (Box 37)
    - International Peace Research Association Conference, Gruningen, Netherlands, 1965 (Box 37)
    - Johnson Foundation Conference on Arms Control, 1960 (Box 37)
    - Leningrad Seminar on Youth and Peaceful Coexistence, 1960; 4 folders (Box 37)
    - Leningrad Seminar on Youth and Peaceful Coexistence, 1960 (Box 38)
    - Lohaus, Adam. (Box 38)
    - London Peace Research Conference, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Mailing Lists, 1960-1961 (Box 38)
    - Michigan Monitors (Box 38)
    - National Conference on World Disarmament and Development, 1961 (Box 38)
    - Pacifism, Printed materials, 1939-1941 (Box 38)
    - Parliamentary Group for World Government, 1965 (Box 38)
    - Peace Pledge Union, 1937 (Box 38)
    - Peace Research Conference
      - Chicago, 1964 (Box 38)
      - Vienna, 1966 (Box 38)
    - Peace Research Institute, 1961-1963 (Box 38)
    - Peace Study Institute, 1959 (Box 38)
    - Princeton Symposium on Internal War, 1961
      - Agenda and Correspondence (Box 38)
      - Papers, 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Project Unicorn, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Saint Louis Seminar on Research in International Conflict and Peace, 1960 (Box 38)
    - SANE, 1958-1961 (Box 38)
    - Society for the Scientific Study of Peace, Proposed, 1960 (Box 38)
    - Student Peace Research Conference, Fort Collins, Colo., 1962 (Box 38)
    - Student Peace Union, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Survival Program, 1963 (Box 38)
    - Turn Toward Peace, 1961-1965 (Box 38)
    - Vietnam Protest, 1965 (Box 38)
    - War Resisters League, 1961 (Box 38)
  - University of Michigan
    - Behavioral Sciences Research Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Center for the Study of Higher Education Conference, 1961 (Box 39)
    - Center for the Study of the University, 1959-1962; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Challenge, 1960-1965 (Box 39)
    - Communication Sciences Program, 1962 (Box 39)
    - Economics Club, 1957-1959 (Box 39)
    - Economics Department
      - General, 1955-1965; 4 folders (Box 39)
      - Curriculum (Box 39)
      - Miscellanea, 12 folders (Box 39)
    - Economics of Health Services and Medical Care Conference, 1962 (Box 39)
    - Library Committee, 1957 (Box 39)
    - LSA Executive Committee, 1959-1961 (Box 39)
    - Mental Health Research Institute, Advisory Committee, 1956-1959; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Research Club, 1960-1961 (Box 39)
    - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs, 1955-1963; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Social Science Research Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 39)
    - Social Work and Social Science Program, 1957-1959; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Student Activities, 1959-1961 (Box 40)
    - Survey Research Center, Committee on Behavioral Science Fund, 1963 (Box 40)
    - Surveys in Behavioral Sciences, circa 1954 (Box 40)
    - UNESCO Council, 1950 (Box 40)
    - University Freedom and Responsibility Committee, 1963 (Box 40)
    - University Press, 1959-1961 (Box 40)
    - Courses and Seminars
      - Integration of the Social Sciences (Economics 353)
        - Competition and Cooperation, 1949-1950 (Box 40)
        - Theory of the Individual, 1950-1951 (Box 40)
        - Growth Theory, 1952-1953
          - Correspondence (Box 40)
          - Boulding Papers (Box 40)
          - Transcripts (Box 40)
            (tapes of presentations are in Box 46)
          - Papers (Box 40)
        - Communication and Information Theory, 1953-1954
          - Correspondence (Box 40)
          - Boulding papers (Box 40)
          - Bibliography (Box 40)
          - Transcripts (Box 40)
            (sound tapes of presentations are in Box 46)
          - Papers (Box 40)
        - Conflict Resolution, 1955-1956; 2 folders (Box 40)
        - Conflict Resolution, 1955-1956; 2 folders (Box 41)
        - Economics and Ethics, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Agricultural Policy (Economics 135), 1950-1965; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Price System (Economics 258-752), 1957-1962 (Box 41)
      - General Systems (Economics 198-498), 1962-1963 (Box 41)
      - Macroeconomics (Economics 751), 1963 (Box 41)
    - Faculty Seminars
      - Social Integration, Summer 1952 (Box 41)
      - Application of Mathematics to the Social Sciences, fall 1952 (Box 41)
      - Research Basis of Social Welfare Practice, 1952-1953 (Box 41)
      - Application of Mathematics to the Social Sciences, 1954 (Box 41)
      - Income Maintenance Programs, 1956-1957; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Economic Development, 1960-1961 (Box 42)
      - Arms Control, 1961-1962 (Box 42)
  - Travel
    - Brazil, 1953 (Box 42)
    - West Indies, 1959-1961
      - Correspondence
        - [alphabetical], 1959-1960 (Box 42)
        - [general], 1959-1960 (Box 42)
        - 1960-1961 (Box 42)
      - Clippings (Box 42)
      - Jamaica (Box 42)
      - British Guiana (Box 42)
      - British Honduras (Box 42)
      - Cuba (Box 42)
      - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Caribbean Studies (Box 42)
    - Europe, 1963 (Box 42)
    - Japan and Korea, 1963-1964 (Box 42)
    - Australia, 1963-1964 (Box 42)
  - Foundations
    - Commonwealth Fund, 1959-1961 (Box 42)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1958-1964; 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Ford Foundation
      - 1952-1954 (Box 42)
      - 1959-1961 (Box 42)
    - Fund for the Republic, 1958-1961 (Box 42)
    - National Science Foundation, 1958 (Box 42)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 1959-1960 (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
- Papers and Publications of others
  - 1931-1961 (Box 42)
  - 1931-1961 (Box 43)
- Speaking engagements
  - 1964-1966, 10 folders (Box 43)
    (arranged alphabetically)
- Financial Records
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed (Box 44)